[Music]
foreign
crochet Channel now today we are
crocheting this beautiful piece
as you wished because I already posted
it on my Instagram on my crochet
Instagram make sure to check it out and
my private one
um I already posted it in like blue gray
tones because it was my last project and
he loved it so much that I was like okay
I have to do a tutorial on it and so
here we are doing this beautiful yellow
piece and I hope you enjoy this video I
hope you're having an amazing day and
have fun crocheted together with me and
don't forget to send me your recreations
because I love to see them and my heart
is so full all the time
um while seeing your pictures so make
sure to tag me or send me pictures in my
DMs slide into my DMs so yeah that's it
enjoy crocheting with me I hope you
understand everything I tried my best to
explain it and
good job
let's start with everything you need
it's not a lot it's as usual just your
yarn whatever color combination and size
of yarn you want and your hook I'm gonna
use 4.0 millimeters
um because I feel like it's best for the
yarn that I'm working with I'm gonna use
different colors like these are all the
same size of yarn I feel like it's
better to use similar sizes of yarn
because then
in the end everything lines up perfectly
and not like one is bigger so the lines
like the row of the bigger yarn is going
to be bigger in the end
um so that's why I'm choosing similar
sizes it doesn't have to be like the
same yarn but just like
similar yarn sizes like for me I'm going
to use
hooked DK soft cotton and I think
this one is another one but I'm gonna
um link everything down below so if you
want to have a look at it I'm going to
use these cotton ones and I'm going to
crochet a bit with mohair because I
really love the look of it you don't
have to but I think it adds like a nice
texture and it's like a lot different to
this
um so yeah this is my color combination
I'm excited to see what color
combinations you are coming up with
and now the first thing that we're going
to do is we're going to make two of
these pieces this is going to be the
front and the back part of your top
um it's the exact same exact same length
and if you want to you can do two
different patterns but I personally
prefer the back and the front to be the
exact same like from the patterns and
colors so I'm gonna do two times this
one and I'm gonna take you through it
it's actually only I think
probably three different patterns that's
it like three different techniques and
um just different colors and
for example here double crochets and
they're triple crochet so it's very easy
to understand and if you understood all
the patterns you can always switch them
up but if you want to do the exact same
that I'm going to do feel free to take
your time and let's get through this
beautiful part
starting off with our first row it's
going to be chain ups and for me it's
going to be 84 chain UPS
um because I feel like that's a very
beautiful look because it's a bit
oversized then in the end I would say
it's like a medium probably
um
but I'm gonna show you what your chain
in the end should look like on your body
like I'm going to compare it to mine
just so you can make sure that it fits
you in the end so right now I did my
slip knot
as always if you don't know like for
example slip knot or slip stitch I'm
gonna link a bit more detail tutorials
like very beginner tutorials in the
description down below because they are
way better at explaining but I am so
um
have a look at that if you don't know
all the steps but for now I'm just gonna
chain up
84 and then we're gonna meet back with
our chain
[Music]
I've been hung up on yesterday
days
[Music]
so this is my chain of 84
um chain ups and now I'm going to show
you what it should look like compared to
your body hello from behind the camera
um so this is the line and if you
watched like the last tutorial and also
this summer sweater top
um You probably will remember that it
was way shorter than this one because
this time I really want the sweater to
have
dropped shoulders so that the sleeve
starts
right here until here it's kind of like
the body part
so
as you can see this is
a lot wider than my shoulders are
because I want this to go till here in
the end we're gonna have one at the
front and one at the back and so the
sleeves are going to start right here
and it's going to be kind of like Drop
shoulder
kind of vibe you know as you can see
it's almost the length of my shoulders
doubled
like twice
so if I take my chain
from this shoulder till here I can kind
of like
almost make it twice from there
I think that's
an okay explanation so make sure that
it's kind of similar to mine and
[Music]
um
if 48 is too short just add more chains
always in
like pairs of two so that it can be
divided through two
that's everything
and now we are going to start with our
first row the first row is going to be
half double crochets
as always for half double crochets
there's a more detailed video link down
below half double crochets means we're
gonna chain up another one
then gonna do the half double crochet
not in the first and not in the second
Loop but in this third one so we're
gonna not go right here
not there but right here
with our half double crochet
and we're gonna continue with this
till the end of the row and it's going
to take a while but that's what we're
gonna do
so it's
it should look like this
let's continue with the half double
crochets
till the end of the row then we're gonna
meet again
I'm about to do my last half double
crochet and we want to change colors in
the next row as you can see here and the
next row is also going to be half double
crochets but in this dark yellow
so what we're going to do is like to
change colors we're going to go for our
half double crochet
pull through the yarn but instead of
like using this one to pull it through
the half double crochet and finish the
half double crochet we're going to take
our new color
for me this darker yellow
and we're already like we can already
cut off
like the excess yarn right here
take
this one
color
and instead of using the old color to
finish the half double crochet we're
going to just use the new one like this
chain up one again and now what I love
to do to give it like a bit of extra
security
um I'm gonna do that in each like color
switching row
um I'm just gonna do like two knots
right here
to secure it make sure to not pull it
too tight
but also not too loose so just that it
looks kind of like a straight perfect
line
now we're going to turn the project
around
so for this row we're also gonna go for
half double crochets but instead of
starting like this I want to take in
these two so that I don't have to sew
them in at the end
so we're gonna do our half double
crochet but with these two on top so go
through
this
but
with these on top just like this
um like I'm gonna leave these here I'm
gonna go right through there take the
yarn pull it through and pull it right
here through so as you can see we're
already kind of sewing these in and you
don't have to do this in the end with
all of them
um so that's what I'm always gonna do
too
and now we're gonna just continue with
half double crochets if you think
um
that you did enough half double crochets
with like sewing these two in you can
always cut it a bit shorter like for me
I feel like
that's long enough
so
I'm gonna pull it a bit tighter
cut through
continue
and
as you can see it's perfectly sewn in
already
oops
and as you can see it's perfectly sewn
in already
and yeah continue with your half double
crochets and then we're going to switch
to the mohair yarn
and
um we're going to use a different
pattern
so let's meet again at the end of roll
number two
I'm gonna go for my last two half double
crochets like
so this is not the last one you can
always if you're not sure if you got the
last Stitch just count them I know it's
a lot to count but better count than in
the end end up with like a piece that
goes like this so I sometimes count too
don't worry so as you can see right here
you have to add one like another one
another half double crochet right here
take this very last Stitch it's always
hard to find
but make sure to get this one too and
now again we are not going to close the
half double crochet with the dark yellow
but with the next color for me it's
gonna be the white mohair as you can see
here and then we are going to do
um single crochets and the next row is
going to be the first mesh pattern with
triple crochets don't worry I'm going to
explain it to you
um but let's first
connect the white mohair yarn
with more hair it's always like because
I'm using white it's a bit maybe
difficult for you to see but I'm going
to try my best
um just use it to close up
the
half double crochet pull everything
tight you can chain up one first or
already two if you want to
um and
knots this together oh
oh probably first cut it before knotting
now you can knot it to get there
dude
I'm gonna again
um
turn around
and now we're going to do single
crochets
as last row I'm gonna take this yarn
with me
but right into this first one
with
single crochet
next one single crochet
like this we're going to leave just on
top the two ends
and I'm gonna go always through these
holes with a single crochet
just like that we're going to continue
till the end of the row
then we're gonna meet for row number
four
Quick Change of light
um now I'm gonna do the last
um single crochet
right here
and then we're gonna start with the next
row
and this is gonna be
triple crochets and then skip Stitch so
it's kind of like a mesh look and to
start we're gonna go for one two
three
four chain UPS
then turn everything around
and now you're gonna go for a triple
crochet which means you're going to take
the yarn twice it's kind of like a
double crochet but just one
more
and now you're gonna go not into this
first one but the second one with your
triple crochet
so like not here but there
and with the triple crochet
then you're gonna chain up one
and your next triple crochet is gonna go
like not
into the next one like here we did our
last triple crochet this would be
usually the next Stitch but we're gonna
go well we're gonna Skip One and go
right here
um I love this Stitch I do it a lot
because I love the look of it it's gonna
look like this in the end
um and we're going to continue like this
like always chain up one then
triple crochet not into this one but
into the second one so we're gonna skip
a stitch
chain up one
triple crochet not here but there
and we're gonna continue like this with
the chain of one and
shave right here till we are at the end
of the row
I'm about to finish the row but before
finishing make sure to check that if you
did like just like me the 84 you should
end up with
of these holes and
[Music]
if um you end up with one less you can
just kind of like sneak one right here
to like make sure to
kind of like
add one even if it's a bit tight in the
end or if like me you kind of messed up
somewhere and end up with three um
single crochets in the end as you can
see like I have three Loops left but I
already have 41 of these holes so I only
need to add another one I'm just gonna
chain up one and gonna do the last
triple crochet knot by skipping one but
by skipping two
um
so that it
kind of like works out in the end
um just like this
um it's not going to be visible in the
end and now for the next row I'm gonna
go for the
light yellow mohair so I'm gonna leave
like two left it's like the last
um
Stitch you would usually do on your
triple crochet like right now you would
close it up right
like right now you would usually use the
y1 to close it off but we're gonna use
the light yellow one
two close
this Stitch
let's pull it through
oops
just pull just pull it through chain up
one pull everything tight
I'm gonna cut off the white yarn
then I'm gonna do two knots
as always
dude
secure everything
and then the next row as you can see
this one was triple crochet and this is
kind of like the same but we're gonna do
I don't know if this word exists but
it's like
a crochet of four
um so it's kind of like the triple
crochet but you're gonna add one loop on
the hook
um I'm gonna show you like we already
chained up one now we're gonna do two
three
four five
because now we're turning it around
and we're gonna do like a triple crochet
but add one more
and then we're gonna go right where this
triple crochet was like right here we're
gonna go in this top Loop
right on top of the triple crochet right
through here
and now we're gonna close so like one
two three four
did you see that so it's kind of like
this but a bit longer now we're gonna
chain up one again
and go for a triple crochet and add one
so you should have four on the hook like
this was the one you already had and it
should be three more
before you are going into this
to right on top of the triple crochet of
the last row
and you're gonna
finish this one up chain up one
and do kind of like this crochet of four
right into this next Loop
and we're going to continue till the end
of the row and it should look like this
well let's finish this row together so
I'm gonna go for the next crochet of
four and I'm gonna go like as you can
see right here you also have to skip one
and then go into this one
like this Loop right here
just make sure that there's a bit of
space left
like this
for the next row it's gonna be again
half double crochets this time again in
this beige color for me and this
actually is the last
kind of difference dish that we're gonna
do and for the following rows you
already then can kind of like take a
look back at the rows that we did before
so
let's do this row because it's slightly
different and then I'm gonna explain to
you how to do the rest
so now again
we're gonna close
this
crochet of four that we did with this
beige color
so make sure that
so slip this through chain up one
then pull everything tight
cut the yarn
make two knots
this
two knots
and then flip your project around
and now we're gonna do our half double
crochets always into these big Loops
like this is gonna count as our first
half double crochet the chain up we did
and so now the next one is gonna go
right here
but we're only going to do one right
here into this first Loop because this
is our second half double crochet kind
of and for these next holes we're always
going to do two half double crochets in
each so it's gonna be one
and two
and then the next one is going to go
into this one one
and two
and we're gonna continue with this till
the end of the row
time to do the last double crochet
make sure that here you can count one
two three four
um
and
the fourth one is where you're gonna add
the last half double crochet
right here
slip it through
so we're in this row right now which
means I'm gonna go for the light yellow
next and with the light yellow we are
gonna do single crochets this time
so grab your yarn
and close the two triple crochet with
the new color chain up one
pull everything tight
cut off the yarn
then we're gonna make two knots again
turn everything around
and make sure to take these two ends
with you while starting with your sand
crochets
um
right into this
first Loop like right here
one
two
three
and we're gonna continue till the end of
the row
and then I'm gonna show you once again
the skip Stitch part but with double
crochets
and then
I'm gonna leave you alone for the rest
of the rows
because after this row like after not
after this but after the next row
everything's gonna repeat just with
different colors
I'm gonna go for my last single crochet
but I'm gonna close it off with the next
yarn color it's this brown or like dark
beige tone
um and I'm gonna cut off this yarn
slip through
the next color chain up one
I'm gonna knot the two ends together
and then we're again gonna go for the
mesh
pattern that we already did but this
time we are going to do double crochets
not triple crochets or like the crochet
of four but we're gonna go
for two chain UPS in the beginning
oh no three chain UPS sorry we're gonna
go for three chain ups at the first one
and then for a double crochet not just
this first one but we're gonna Skip One
and we're gonna go right there
with a double crochet then chain up one
again and the double crochet is gonna go
knotted to the next one well like right
here so we're gonna Skip One
the same that we did before but instead
of triple crochets we're gonna go for
double crochets
and that's what we're going to do till
the end of the row so
should look like this
and we're gonna meet at the end of
roll number
seven or eight wherever we are
I'm about to do the last
skip Stitch and double crochet
right here
and then
we can add the next color for the next
row
if you're not sure if you did enough of
these always make sure to count them or
to compare them to these and now
I'm gonna explain to you how to do the
next rows or like in which order I'm
gonna kind of like write it down for you
just like in the last tutorial
so yeah let's go right there
okay guys so I wrote everything down for
you because we ended
because like this row is where we ended
and from this point like till here till
the end
um the last rows are gonna repeat just
in different orders and different colors
and if you want to you can totally
choose by yourself
in which order or which color you want
to put the patterns but if you need some
more guidance you can just copy what I
did so
um take a screenshot right here and from
top to bottom
um I wrote down for you like each row
row one two three what we did here and
if you look like for example row 12
single crochets and you forgot what the
single crochets are you can just skip
back to row three because they're like
also the blue point
which means we did single crochets there
too
I hope that makes sense
[Music]
I just finished both of the
big Parts like the front and the back
part and now we want to connect it and
that means that we are going to
put these on top of each other like this
big piece
and
this one on top in the same order
like right now
it's
exactly the same
um order if you did different ones don't
worry it will still work out and now we
are going to connect
at these side Parts about 10 to 15
centimeters it kind of depends on how
off shoulder you want to wear it because
we're going to connect right here
I'm gonna do probably 12 centimeters and
on the other side the same and this
space where we don't connect is going to
be where your head is going to go
through so make sure that in the end it
fits but you can always
um in the end open up some more or close
them a bit more so yeah let's start and
I am going to link a video for the
connecting Stitch that I'm using down
below because
I don't really know myself what I'm
doing
so I better not try to explain it to you
I'm going to use this dark yellow color
just because I'm kind of like think it's
gonna look cute compared to this white
um and I'm just going to start
connecting
you could also hand sew it together
or machine sew just how you like it most
I'm gonna crochet together
with the tutorial that I'm gonna Link in
the description
so go have a look at that
meet me when you
connected everything just like I'm gonna
do right now
[Music]
so this is what my connecting Stitch
looks like I'm right now at 13
centimeters I'm gonna leave it there I'm
just gonna do a loose Slip Knot Before
really securing it and gonna cut off the
yarn a bit more generously than usual so
that if it's a bit too loose when I try
it on later then I can still change it
so I'm Gonna Leave This little Loop here
and gonna do it on the other side and
then we're gonna try it on
so here we are both sides are connected
and now you can
try it on just like this and if you want
it a bit more tight around your neck you
can kind of like add some more
connecting stitches but for me I like it
because I feel like I can also wear a
bit of shoulder but it's not too much so
it's not
kind of like slipping down all the time
so I think I'm going to leave it like
that next step is we're going to connect
it here like these two the side Parts
only a tiny bit I'm going to show you
because
that's done
so now that we tried it on and realized
that we're happy
um we can
ever works we can just chain up two one
two and slip it through and pull it
tight so that as you can see it's very
secure
other side too
now that we connected this top part
we're gonna go to the side part of the
project and right here down there we're
going to connect around
um
I think five centimeters yeah five
centimeter is gonna be good
um so you can use the same technique as
you did before and just connect probably
till here
it's around five centimeters
I just connected
um the side part I did a bit more than
five centimeters it's now around six to
seven
and I'm gonna do my last Stitch now and
then we are going to start with our
sleeve yay so go add your your last dish
and then chain up one
another one and now we are going to
start with single crochets and
as you can see we now have this little
hole right here and we're always going
to crochet around
just like this and gonna connect in the
end then chain up one or two and then
continue
we're going to start with one right here
and
right here for example because we did
like
two chain UPS we're gonna do two set
and here because we did two chain UPS
we're gonna also do two of the half
double crochets right here
that's how it's going to work for the
whole arm so for example right here we
have a single crochet which means we're
gonna add one here
right here we had four chain UPS which
means we're gonna do four half double
crochets right here
and that's what we're gonna do for the
whole sleeve and then I'm gonna meet you
when you're back here so just continue
with
one of the half double crochets if we
did for example a half double crochet in
this direction or a single crochet if we
did two chain UPS like here you're gonna
add two if we did three we're gonna add
three
so yeah that's basically it so let's
meet when we're finished with the first
row of the sleeves
I just finished with my last half double
crochet and now we're going to connect
it but make sure to only connect it with
a slip stitch so
go to your first Stitch and slip the
yarn through
so go through your first slip stitch and
now we want to connect again which means
that we're going to use the color we
want to use in the next row so for me
I'm gonna start with this light yellow
again
so
I'm gonna connect the row with a slip
stitch but while using this new color so
slip it through
like this and now chain up one
two
and for me because I now want to do this
pattern
this one
I'm gonna chain up another one
and now I'm going to start with my
double crochets while skipping one and
actually
this now is going to be all the time the
exact same than what we did at the body
part you can decide whatever order you
want to do the patterns in and whatever
colors you want to do and just randomly
play around with them
so
have fun
and I don't think I have to explain
anything else to you because the only
thing you want to do now is always
crochet around make sure to connect it
in the end with a slip stitch
um
and then for the next row again chain up
one or two one if you do single crochets
two if you do double crochets or just
like we did in the other rows like for
example at this one we did chain up
three in the beginning if you're not
sure always have look back at the
previous rows we did but I think it
should be clean now so just go on with
crocheting around until you're happy
with the length on length of the sleeve
and then
um you can start with the second sleeve
then we're finished
that's it already crazy right so
continue with that I'm gonna continue
with both sleeves and then I'm going to
show you in the end what my final
sweater summer sweater looks like
um and I'm excited to see yours so have
fun finishing the sleeves
[Music]
that was the tutorial of this beautiful
top I hope you enjoyed and I hope you
had a good time crocheting with me I
tried my best to explain everything as
good as possible
and can't wait to see you in the next
crochet project make sure to
subscribe and everything check out my Ig
for more crochet content and
yeah send me some inspo if you have some
because
I'm not sure what my next crochet
project is going to be
still haven't decided
so yeah have an amazing day send me your
Recreations I have to see them
and have a wonderful day bye
[Music]